Todd Stoffer

Raleigh, NC 27604 | (301) 906-3525 | toddstoffer@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/toddstoffer

SUMMARY

I develop and implement technology rich solutions to enhance organizational missions and workflows. I have nearly a decade of experience managing information technology and software development projects. I am a detail-oriented, deadline driven, and well-rounded professional with sharp technical and communication skills.

Key Skills

Software Development: Ruby on Rails | Python | DevOps | VM Management | Version Control **Technical Instruction:** Curriculum Development | Content Design | Classroom Facilitation **Technical Support:** Windows/OSX/Linux | Virtual Machine Support | Hardware Support

Professional Experience

North Carolina State University,

Raleigh, NC

Digital Technologies Development Librarian

09/2015-Present

- Develop and maintain Ruby on Rails applications
- Develop and maintain web applications using Jekyll, Python and Javascript
- Lead curriculum development and classroom instruction of technical workshops
- Adapt workshop curriculum based on participant feedback, and post workshop survey responses
- Research, analyze and implement open-source software tools to enhance workshop instruction
- Increase cross-departmental collaboration through the integration of new technologies into existing workflows

University of Maryland

College Park, MD 06/2012-08/2015

Information Technology Coordinator

- Managed the development and design of new campus walk-in IT service center
- Managed a student staff of 20 employees
- Provided direct supervision of the primary campus walk-in IT service center
- Developed workflow process improvements that enabled a 200% growth in traffic while maintaining positive customer feedback and a high NPS score.
- Developed the policies, training and technical support materials required to maintain a high level of customer satisfaction
- Provided implementation testing and created internal training documentation for the rollout of all new enterprise software solutions
- Served as a project management team member for enterprise-level IT systems and services

Market Hardware Bethesda, MD 03/2010-06/2012

Project Manager

- Managed the design, build and implementation phases of client websites and marketing solutions
- Provided technical advice and support to the sales team on all products
- Researched, tested and implemented new web technologies
- Created and maintained technical documentation and training materials
- Responsible for analysis, design and maintenance of internal network and systems

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts in Political Science, 2009, Colorado State University, Ft. Collins, CO Master of Library and Information Science, 2015, University of Maryland, College Park, MD